<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE manual SYSTEM "flowframtk.dtd">
<manual fontenc="T1">
  <preamble>
    <!-- Document Info -->
    <title>User Manual for <dict tag="appname"/> version
      <dict tag="appversion" /></title>
    <author>Nicola L. C. Talbot<br/><url www="www.dickimaw-books.com" /></author>
<!--
    <author>Another Author<br />Affliation or URL</author>
    <author>Translated by Some One<br />Affliation or URL</author>
-->
    <date><dict tag="appdate" /></date>

    <!-- Define Abbreviations -->

    <newacro short="GUI" long="graphical user interface" tag="gui">
      An application with windows and buttons in which the user
      can point and click with the mouse.
    </newacro>

    <newacro short="JDK" long="Java Standard Edition SDK" tag="jdk">
      A development environment for building
       applications, applets and components using the Java
       programming language.
    </newacro>

    <newacro short="JRE" long="Java Runtime Environment" tag="jre"> 
      Allows end-users to run Java applications.
    </newacro>

    <newacro short="JVM" long="Java Virtual Machine" tag="jvm">
      Also known as the Java Runtime Environment.
    </newacro>

    <newacro short="MDI" long="multiple-Document interface" tag="mdi" >
      A main (parent) window containing child
       windows allowing you to process several documents in
       parallel.
    </newacro>

    <newacro short="SVG" long="scalable vector graphics" tag="svg" >
      A Modularized language for describing
      two-dimensional vector and mixed vector/raster graphics in XML.
    </newacro>


    <!-- Define Terms. If a description is included it's a glossary
         term otherwise it goes in the index -->

    <newterm tag="jdr" text="JDR">
      <app/>'s native binary format. Files in this format 
      should have the extension <ext>jdr</ext>.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="ajr" text="AJR">
      <app/>'s native ASCII format. Files in this format 
      should have the extension <ext>ajr</ext>. This format is 
      primarily provided to assist conversion to and from JDR files 
      or for version control.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="Java" text="Java">
     A platform-independent object-orientated language.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="JavaHelp" text="JavaHelp">
     An optional package of the JRE enabling applications to use a native browser
     to display help topics.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="grid" text="grid" >
     Tick marks located at regular intervals on the canvas. The grid can be locked so
     that new points will be placed at the tick nearest the specified
     position.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="toolbars" text="toolbars">
    The two panels containing buttons, the horizontal toolbar is positioned at
    the top of <app/>'s main window, the vertical toolbar is
    positioned along the left edge of the main window.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="statusbar" text="status bar">
    The status bar is the horizontal panel positioned along the bottom of
    <app/>'s main window.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="rulers" text="rulers">
    The two panels containing the horizontal and vertical rulers.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="canvas" text="canvas" plural="canvases">
    The white area on which you construct your picture.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="shape" text="shape">
    Either a path, text-path or a composite shape.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="path" text="path">
    A shape made up of line segments, moves and cubic Bézier segments
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="textarea" text="text area">
    An object consisting of a single line of text. The text may be moved,
    scaled, rotated, sheared or converted to a path.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="textpath" text="text-path">
    A composite object formed by combining a path and a text area
    to create a text along a path effect. The underlying path is
    only visible when editing the text-path object using the edit path
    function. Transformations (rotating, scaling and shearing) are
    applied to the path not to the text.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="compositeshape" text="composite shape">
    A shape that is described by an underlying shape
    and a means of transforming it, such as apply symmetry or replicas.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="symmetricshape" text="symmetric shape">
    A composite shape that is formed by the underlying shape
    added to its reflection in a line a symmetry. Depending on how it's
    created, the symmetric shape may be drawn as a single shape, or the
    underlying shape and its reflection may be drawn independently of
    each other. The line of symmetry has two control points that can be
    adjusted to change the overall shape.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="pattern" text="pattern">
    A composite shape formed by repeatedly applying a given
    transformation on a shape. Each pattern has a specified number of
    replicas. The underlying shape may or may not be visible. The
    pattern mode determines whether the underlying path and replicas are
    drawn in one go (single mode) or whether they are drawn
    independently of each other (multi-mode). Transformations (rotating,
    scaling and shearing) are applied to the path not to the text.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="rotationalpattern" text="rotational pattern">
    A pattern where the replicas are created
    by rotating the underlying path. In addition to the control points
    defining the underlying shape, rotational patterns also have a control
    point that governs the point of rotation.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="scaledpattern" text="scaled pattern">
    A pattern where the replicas are created
    by scaling the underlying path. In addition to the control points
    defining the underlying shape, scaled patterns also have two control
    points governing the scale anchor and the scale direction.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="spiralpattern" text="spiral pattern">
    A pattern where the replicas are created
    by rotating and translating the underlying path so that the replicas
    are aligned along a spiral. In addition to the control points
    defining the underlying shape, spiral patterns also have two control points
    that govern the anchor and offset.
    </newterm>

    <newterm tag="vectorgraphics" text="vector graphics">
    </newterm>

  </preamble>

  <document>
   <node tag="introduction" type="chapter" title="Introduction">
   <p>
   <app/><footnote>This application is a replacement for the now-obsolete
   JpgfDraw (<b>J</b>ava <b>pgf</b>-code generating <b>draw</b>ing application).
   In fact, it's actually just been renamed and the code refactored.</footnote>
   is a <term tag="vectorgraphics"/> application written in <term tag="Java"/>, with a 
   <acr tag="gui"/>.
   </p>
   <p>
   Under construction.
   </p>
   </node>
   <node type="chapter" tag="licence" title="Licence" >
   <p>
   <app/> is licensed under the terms of the GNU General Public License.
   <app/> depends on the following third party library whose jar files is
   in the <tt>lib</tt> directory: Java Help
   (<url www="https://javahelp.java.net/"/>).
   </p>
     <verbtabinput src="LICENSE"/>
   </node>
   <printglossary />
   <printacronyms />
   <printindex />
  </document>
</manual>

